Contact

mohamedmd2500@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/asafmohammed (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

GenAl

Workflow Automation
Al automation

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Tamil (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Elementary)

Certifications

Python Essential Training

SQL (Intermediate) Certificate

Agile at Work: Reporting with Agile

Charts and Boards

Agile at Work: Planning with Agile

User Stories

Agile at Work: Building Your Agile

Team

Honors-Awards

Best Performer

Asaf Mohammed

Al Generalist | Data & Automation

Tamil Nadu, India

Summary

Data Analyst in ZoomInfo with more than 2 years of experience with spreadsheet tools like Excel and Google Sheets and more than a year of experience in SQL. Currently pursuing data skills like Python and Tableau. My previous experience includes the position of Research Analyst in Altrata where I had been recognised as best performer multiple times through my tenure.

Experience

ZoomInfo

Data Engineer

June 2023 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Chennai

- Developed Python scripts for email validation automation and data quality checks and saved about 10 man days' effort per quarter.
- Developed and optimized SQL queries in Snowflake for analytics and reporting
- Developed Salesforce Utils script and SingleStore Utils script from scratch using Python which helped in cross team adaptability.
- Developed PDF reports and Tableau visualizations for internal teams
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to support decision-making with clean data pipelines
- Contributed to GCP-based Full File Collector scripts and data ingestion workflows
- Supported analysis of credit usage and free credit patterns across clients using Tableau

Altrata

2 years 9 months

Senior Research Analyst August 2022 - June 2023 (11 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

ALTRATA is a part of Euromoney Institutional Investor PLC, and includes BoardEx, Boardroom Insiders, RelSci, WealthEngine and Wealth-X.

- Organization profiling to accumulate business knowledge on competitors, possibilities, clients and providers
- 2. The executive postings with biographies, instructive foundation and expert affiliations.
- 3. Lead inside and out data examination using progressed and conventional strategies.
- 4. Contribute in the definition, improvement and organization of programming items and basic organization models.
- 5. Explored, examined and deciphered information. Remedied mistakes in inner data set.
- 6. Provided timely feedback to Team leader and consistently met deadlines.

Research Analyst

October 2020 - July 2022 (1 year 10 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

ALTRATA is a part of Euromoney Institutional Investor PLC, and includes BoardEx, Boardroom Insiders, RelSci, WealthEngine and Wealth-X.

- 1. Organization profiling to accumulate business knowledge on competitors, possibilities, clients and providers
- 2. The executive postings with biographies, instructive foundation and expert affiliations.
- 3. Lead inside and out data examination using progressed and conventional strategies.
- 4. Contribute in the definition, improvement and organization of programming items and basic organization models.

- 5. Explored, examined and deciphered information. Remedied mistakes in inner data set.
- 6. Provided timely feedback to Team leader and consistently met deadlines.

Relationship Science

2 years 9 months

Senior Research Analyst

August 2022 - June 2023 (11 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- 1. Organization profiling to accumulate business knowledge on competitors, possibilities, clients and providers
- 2. The executive postings with biographies, instructive foundation and expert affiliations.
- 3. Lead inside and out data examination using progressed and conventional strategies.
- 4. Contribute in the definition, improvement and organization of programming items and basic organization models.
- 5. Explored, examined and deciphered information. Remedied mistakes in inner data set.
- 6. Provided timely feedback to Team leader and consistently met deadlines.

Research Analyst

October 2020 - July 2022 (1 year 10 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- 1. Organization profiling to accumulate business knowledge on competitors, possibilities, clients and providers
- 2. The executive postings with biographies, instructive foundation and expert affiliations.
- 3. Lead inside and out data examination using progressed and conventional strategies.

- 4. Contribute in the definition, improvement and organization of programming items and basic organization models.
- 5. Explored, examined and deciphered information. Remedied mistakes in inner data set.
- 6. Provided timely feedback to Team leader and consistently met deadlines.

Education

Aalim Muhammed Salegh College Of Engineering
Bachelor of Engineering, Mechanical Engineering (2015 - 2019)